<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Satisfying Constraints</title>
    <description>A blog about information.
</description>
    <link>https://kuruga.github.io//</link>
    <atom:link href="https://kuruga.github.io//feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 01:40:24 +0900</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2016 01:40:24 +0900</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.1.6</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Probability Trees</title>
        <description>The purpose of this post is to illustrate and define the concept of probability in terms of possibilities. Take a look at the following binary tree. It depicts the possible outcomes of three successive coin flips of a coin with the sides showing 0 and 1. Assuming the coin is fair, different arrangements of results may vary in the number of possible ways in which they could happen. For instance, having two 1s and one 0 as the outcome of three coin flips can be realized by the following highlighted paths: Three out of eight possible paths can realize this...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/11/Probabilities.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/11/Probabilities.html</guid>
        
        <category>probability</category>
        
        <category>trees</category>
        
        
        <category>statistics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coins</title>
        <description>In this post I illustrate the logic behind binomial probability distributions and how this logic applies when large numbers of samples are obtained. Content Decisions from Uncertainty Large Numbers Binomial Experiments From Possibilities to Probabilities The Pascal Triangle The Binomial Coefficient Biased Binomial Distributions Decisions from Uncertainty A decision between two exclusive options can become difficult when we have no apparent reason or authority to choose one over the other. A common way to resolve such a dilemma is to flip a coin and assign one choice to each side of it. If the coin should land showing heads, one...</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jul 2016 22:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/11/coins.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/11/coins.html</guid>
        
        <category>decisions</category>
        
        <category>probability</category>
        
        <category>large numbers</category>
        
        <category>bernoulli</category>
        
        <category>binomial</category>
        
        <category>pascal triangle</category>
        
        <category>probability distributions</category>
        
        <category>R</category>
        
        
        <category>statistics</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Welcome</title>
        <description>Learning Statistics with R During early summer I taught a module on statistical programming with R as part of a course on statistical methods. The course has now finished but I believe that some of the material which I prepared can still be of use and have therefore decided to recycle parts of it in a series of blog posts. Instead of recreating the course, these posts will focus on individual topics and are not meant to teach programming with R from the beginning. If you are searching for a basic introduction into R such as this one you should...</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2016 23:00:00 +0900</pubDate>
        <link>https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/10/FirstPost.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kuruga.github.io//statistics/2016/07/10/FirstPost.html</guid>
        
        <category>R,</category>
        
        <category>test</category>
        
        
        <category>statistics</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
